americasbestvalueinn.com 2019-12-14

# Privacy | Red Lion Hotels

At RLH Corporation we value your loyalty and are committed to safeguarding your personal information. Our Privacy Policy provides insight into our practices relating to the security and usage of your data. As you read this policy, know that your concerns are our concerns and we will always treat your data with the utmost care and respect.

We understand that your privacy is important. This Privacy Policy identifies the types of information we collect, how we use your information, and what options you have regarding these practices.

* * *

### Summary of how we use your data

RLH Corporation websites and mobile apps are designed to allow our customers to interact with our corporate offices, brands, and hotels. We use your personal data in various ways to facilitate this.

Some of the ways RLH Corporation uses personal data is when:

  * You inquire about our services;
  * You make a reservation;
  * You complete a transaction at one of our hotels;
  * You utilize our banquet facilities;
  * You become a Hello Rewards Member; and when
  * You apply for a position at our company

Our privacy statement describes how RLH Corporation will make use of your personal information when you visit our websites or app, when we communicate with you and when you interact with us:

  * What information we collect and why;
  * Our use of data and analytics;
  * The legal basis on which we process your information;
  * Who we share your personal information with, where and when;
  * Your rights over your personal information;
  * How you can get in contact with us to discuss your personal information;
  * How to opt-out of direct marketing;
  * Who the data controller over your personal information is; and
  * How long we will keep your personal information.
  * Where we might transfer your data internationally we make sure that it is protected according to the standards required by applicable law.
  * You also have various rights over your personal data including a right to object to some of the processing of your personal data that RLH Corporation carries out.
  * Our website and our app may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy notices. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

* * *

### What information do we collect and why?

We collect and process personal data about you when you interact with our websites or our app, purchase or express an interest in receiving products or services from us or subscribing to our communications. This includes:

**Your contact details including your name, mailing and email address and telephone number.**

  * To contact you in order for us to manage, administer and provide our products and services to you.
  * To respond to any correspondence and service-related enquiries you send to us in respect of our products or services.
  * To provide you with relevant information such as reservation confirmation, updates, or changes.
  * We might use this information to market products and services to you where you have consented to this.
  * We might also use this information to market RLH Corporation products and services to you (including via electronic means) and to inform you about news, events and other information, to the extent you have not opted-out and to the extent such marketing relates to a product and/or service we have previously provided you or to a product or service you are communicating with us or have expressed an interest in.
  * We may use this information to collect payment from you, for example where payments for reservations or services are overdue.
  * We may also receive this information from licensees of our brands and hotels (e.g. third-party reservation websites or marketing and promotional partners) where you have opted-in with that licensee for your information being shared with us.
  * To communicate any updates to you including any changes to our services, the terms and conditions of any services which we have provided to you, any changes to this Privacy Notice and to our websites or app.
  * To invite you to give feedback and/or take part in market research or surveys to assist us with improving our guest services.

**Identity details including your title, name, date of birth, gender,** **user name** **, social media handles or another similar identifier.**

  * To register you as a guest in our hotels, to establish your identity and to ensure that we are corresponding with and providing products and services to the correct person.
  * To enable your participation in a prize draw or competition which you have entered.
  * We might also use this information to market RLH Corporation products and services to you (including via electronic means) and to inform you about news, events and other information, to the extent you have not opted-out and to the extent such marketing relates to a product and/or service we have previously provided you or to a product or service you are communicating with us or have expressed an interest in.
  * We may use this information to collect payment of debts from you, for example where payments for reservations or services are overdue.
  * We may also receive this information from licensees of our brands and hotels (e.g. third-party reservation websites or marketing and promotional partners) where you have opted-in with that licensee for your information being shared with us.
  * We only collect information about your gender for statistical purposes and to personalize the products and services we offer to you.

**Financial information including bank account and payment card details.**

  * Your payment card details may be collected via our call centers, websites, or app. This information is used solely for billing purposes by our payment services providers. Your payment card information is encrypted and transmitted to our payment services providers.
  * We may collect your bank account details to process subscription-based services you enter into with us.

**Details of payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us including any feedback.**

  * To allow us to provide you with any products or services you have purchased from us.
  * To administer any refunds that we provide to you.
  * To enable you to track historical transactions with us through your account.
  * To establish whether other products / services that we may wish to contact you about (where we are entitled to do so) are relevant.
  * To respond to comments / complaints you or others may send to us.
  * To improve and protect our products, platforms, content, services, websites, and apps.
  * To check your eligibility for products and services which you wish to purchase from us.

**Your preferences in receiving marketing communications from us and any third parties (including any consents you have given us) and confirmation of whether or not we should contact you.**

  * To make sure that we only send marketing information to you where we are entitled to do so.

**Your Hello Rewards membership status.**

  * We receive a 'yes' or 'no' answer at our request from the official supporters' club as to whether you are a member.
  * This assists with ticketing and providing benefits to members.

**Your username and password, purchases or reservations made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.**

  * We will use this information to show you information that is relevant to you including your account information and history to allow you to administer your account.
  * We also use some of this information for analytics purposes, which are described in more detail below under 'Our use of data analytics'.

**Technical data about your access to and use of the website and app.**

  * We may use various technologies to collect and analyze information about your activity on our website, including "cookies", IP address (from which we may infer your country of location), the type of device you are using, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the device you use to access our website or app and information about whether you open our communications, which content you have viewed and other page interaction information.
  * This is primarily to help us better understand how our guests use our digital platforms to enable us to create better content and more relevant communications.
  * A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer and saves information about your activity on the website. In some instances, personal information (such as your email address) may be embedded in a cookie when you visit our site. You may choose to disable cookies in your browser, but please note that doing so may affect your ability to properly interact with our website.

**Information relating to any access, disability and/or dietary requirements you may have.**

  * We will generally only request this information where it is needed for reservations, banquets, or other hospitality purposes. For example where you have a reservation at a hotel so that we can make sure there are suitable accessibility arrangements in place.

**Information required by law.**

  * This may include, for example, where we need guest registration and purchase information for federal tax law, local fire & safety regulations require we store customer information for guest protections, or in response to requests by government or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation.
  * We will only keep copies of your identity documents for as long as it takes us to verify your identity and will then securely delete those copies.
  * We use software that analyses the copies of identity documents that you provide to us which may automatically make a decision about your identity. However, where an automatic decision of this kind is made, you will always have the opportunity to challenge it if you disagree with the decision made.
  * We will not use the copies we take of your identity documents for any other purpose.

Please note that we may use any of the data described above to prevent, investigate and/or report fraud, terrorism, misrepresentation, security incidents or crime, in accordance with applicable laws.

* * *

### Our use of data and analytics

In order to maintain a high level of customer service, we may use your personal information to:

  * provide you with products and services that you request (e.g. to complete a reservation);
  * process your financial information to complete a purchase;
  * communicate with you about your Hello Rewards membership;
  * send you announcements, program updates, and special offers and promotions for our products and services or third-party products and services;
  * improve our services and website content via market research, such as customer feedback surveys;
  * respond to an employment request; and to improve your overall RLH Corporation experience.

We evaluate, categorize and profile personal data to help us personalize services and communications on our platforms and on third party platforms such as social media. This also helps prevent unwanted communications from filling up your inbox. This helps us understand and provide a better experience to our customers, improve and protect our organization and carry out research connected to our products and services.

**Internal research and analysis:** We carry out research and analysis on our customers to determine the success of campaigns and promotions, better understand behavior and responses and identify patterns and trends. This helps inform our approach and make RLH Corporation a stronger and more effective organization. Understanding our customers, their interests, and what they care about also helps us provide a better experience.

**Analysis and grouping:** We analyze the data we collect about customers to identify common characteristics and preferences. We do this by assessing various types of information including behavior, for example, previous activity or demographic information, such as age or location. This allows us to ensure you receive the communications, products and information which are most important to you.

**Profiling to help us understand our customers:** We profile customers on the basis of various criteria including their interests, general geographic location, website/app activity and socioeconomic and age groups. At times, we may also use aggregated, anonymized lifestyle data obtained from third parties to supplement our profiles. This information helps us to ensure communications are relevant and timely and to offer new products and services that may be of interest to our customers.

Several of these analytics activities rely on the use of cookies. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website or platforms may become inaccessible or not function properly.

* * *

### Legal basis for processing personal data

Our legal basis for collecting and using your personal data will depend on the personal data concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

If we ask you to provide personal data to comply with a legal requirement, to perform a transaction with you (such as making a reservation), or for any other reason with your explicit consent, we can provide details why to you on request. We will advise you at the time whether the collection of your personal data is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal data).

If we collect and use your personal data in reliance to our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), you may request that we provide you with information about what those legitimate interests are by contacting us using the details at 'How do I get in touch with you?' below.

* * *

### Who will we share this data with, where and when?

Data collected might be shared with third party service providers, who will process it on behalf of RLH Corporation for the purposes identified above. Such third parties include providers of social media platforms and search engines, providers of services to the club such as website hosting, app developers, software providers, maintenance providers, payment providers, identity verification providers, video streaming companies, mailing companies and marketing services,

Personal data may be shared with government authorities and/or law enforcement officials if required for the purposes above, if mandated by law or if required for the legal protection of our legitimate interests in compliance with applicable laws.

We will only share your data with a third party for the purpose of them directly marketing to you where you have consented to such data sharing (for example, when entering into a specific marketing promotion where we have partnered with that third party).

We may need to store or transfer your personal information to entities that store data outside the United States of America (USA), some of which might not protect privacy rights as extensively as the USA. We will make appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Notice. Further details of these safeguards can be provided for your review on request by contracting our Data Protection Officer using the contact information set out under the heading ‘How do I get in touch with you or your data protection officer?’ below.

* * *

### What rights do I have?

You have the right to **ask us for a copy** of your personal data; to **correct, delete** or **restrict** (stop any active) processing of your personal data; and to **obtain the personal data you provide to us for the purchase of products or services or with your consent in a structured,** **machine readable** **format.**

In addition, you can **object to the processing** of your personal data in some circumstances (in particular, where we don’t have to process the data to meet a contractual or other legal requirement, or where we are using the data for direct marketing).

Wherever we rely on your consent, you will always be able to withdraw that consent, although we may have other legal grounds for processing your data for other purposes, such as those set out above. In some cases, we might able to send you direct marketing without your consent, where we rely on our legitimate interests. You have an absolute right to opt-out of direct marketing, or profiling we carry out for direct marketing, at any time. You can do this by following the instructions in the communication where this is an electronic message, or by contacting us using the details set out below:

These **rights may be limited** , for example if fulfilling your request would reveal personal data about another person, or if you ask us to delete information which we are required by law to keep or have compelling legitimate interests in keeping.

To exercise any of these rights, you can get in touch with us or our data protection officer using the details set out below. If you have unresolved concerns, you have the **right to complain** to an appropriate data protection supervisory authority.

* * *

#### Minors

We do not sell products or services for purchase by minors (defined as individuals under the age of 18), except in jurisdictions where doing so may be required by applicable law. Moreover, except where required by law, we do not knowingly collect personal information from minors. If you believe a minor has submitted personal information through our website, please contact us so we may remove their information from our database and email marketing campaigns.

### How do I get in touch with you or your data protection officer?

We hope that we can satisfy queries you may have about the way we process your data. You can get in touch with RLH Corporation’s Data Protection Officer if you have any concerns or queries about how we process your data at DPO@rlhco.com or by writing to the following address:

**RLH Corporation C/O Data Protection Officer**  
RLH Corporation  
1550 Market St #350  
Denver, CO 80202

* * *

### How do I opt-out of direct marketing?

There are several ways you can stop direct marketing communications from us:

  * click the 'unsubscribe' link in any email marketing communications which we send you and make changes to your preferences
  * if you have a Hello Rewards account registered on our, log-in to the account and update or change your preferences; or
  * contact our Guest Relations team using our [Need Help?](https://www.redlion.com/contact) page.

Please note that you may continue to receive communications for a short period after changing your preferences while all our systems are fully updated.

* * *

### Which RLH Corporation entity is my data controller, and which affiliates might my data be shared with?

The data controller for your information is Red Lion Hotels Corporation, except where you have consented to us sharing your data with third party partners for direct marketing purposes where the data controller will be such third-party partner.

* * *

### How long will you retain my data?

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy please contact:

**RLH Corporation**  
1550 Market St #350  
Denver, CO 80202
